Hello everyone,
This morning "Guai Ge" (from Guai Ge Da Ye) and I
went to harvest two wasps hives
This one is about 10 lbs
This one is about 5-6 lbs
Now, we've brought them back
Brother Guai has lots of them
so he gave these to me today
Now, let's prepare them
we are at my uncle's place
Let's try this new dish together
The wasps are aggressive when they are out
haha, it will be disastrous if we let them out
that would be setting the wasps to go away on their own
[laughter]
don't touch it, you might get stung in the butt
look, they are looking for opening
there was a wasp
on the day of...
it stung me
it flew away as soon as I touched it
but the sting left a scar here
yeah, on the day when we...
let me take a look
it's not swollen
it was swollen when I just got stung
the skin here looks dead
Then I applied medicine on the area
???? I applied three to four times
can't believe it had the guts to sting you
You are "Huo Yun Xie Shen"
[laughter]
So how are we going to cook these
The wasps?
yeah
We will drown the wasps in water first
we can't tough them now, they will sting you
what do we do after the wasps are drown?
the more developed wasps (pupae) can be fried
the under-developed wasps (larvae) can be steamed first,
picked and sieved out afterwards,
fried with oil at last
stir-fry doesn't taste as good as deep fry
fry to burnt
I was afraid you would say "Kuan You"???
[laughter]
Don't worry about using too much oil
For you, there's no such thing as too much oil
yep, no such thing
alright, I'll go ahead and drown these first
in the water tank over there
we need to break it all up before putting it in the water
They are not dead yet. They can hold longer breaths than human
Do not let go
If we put our hand in, would we get stung?
100% it will sting you
Are you scared?
I am not scared.
Stay away if a wasp approaches you, okay?
Okay.
Because they "bite" (sting) people.
Sting people.
Yes, sting people.
[laughter]
Daddy, I like eating the white stuff.
I will cook it for you later, okay?
Is that okay?
Okay.
We need to deal with the more developed wasps first,
before we can deal with the larvae
You see, all the black are
wasps.
And they are definitely still alive
Crack it open and shake
[laughter]
For real.
There's one still moving.
Pick it up. Over there.
Rinse it with water.
Get some water over here.
Do you need sifter?
yeah, need sifter.
Look, this is a wasp.
Do you see it?
I am afraid to eat this.
I can only eat this (larvae).
The white ones, right?
I am afraid to eat this.
I can only eat this.
Which one are you not afraid to eat?
I am not afraid to eat the white ones.
The black ones look scary, right?
I can eat the black ones too.
Is that right?
Yes.
So brave.
Wow.
I will pour the entire bottle in.
It's up to you.
haha, Kuan You (?)
This bottle of rapeseed oils smells really good. Didn't we make it?
Yeah, at Ba Tiao (place)
we harvested the rapeseeds and deep-fried them
It smells really good.
The rapeseed oil has to be cooked
until there are no more foamy bubbles
It is more fragrant that way
The presence of foamy bubbles means the oil is uncooked
We have to cook it thoroughly
Plus, frying these larvae requires the oil to be very hot.
We have less oil,
more larvae.
Once submerged, larvae cannot stay in the oil for too long.
Over frying can cause bitterness,
less fragrant
So reaching the correct temperature in both heat and oil is a big challenge
By the way, I do not recommend anyone to harvest wasp hives
Please do not copy.
I brought this here specifically for this purpose
For deep-frying meat and stuff.
You can use this.
Exactly.
Now the oil has reached the right temperature
Let's put this in
Watch out for the splashing
This oil is for food purpose.
You can put as much oil as you like.
As much as you like.
Really?
Of course.
That's easy then.
That's why I said it.
That's good to know.
I can put as much as I want then.
The color is not ready.
It's very close to done
It's almost done.
I would know when it's done.
the texture needs to be right
Want to try, honey?
It smells really good.
Is the color ready yet?
Not yet.
Yeah, it smells really good now.
Take it out once it's done. Is the fire out?
The fire is out.
It's ready to be served.
Golden brown color.
Sprinkle some salt
Like this
Here take one.
Here take two.
Give one to mama too.
I've already given mama two pieces.
Give her another piece.
two larvae!
three larvae..
I'll feed you one too.
Why aren't you feeding me?
Aren't you going to give Papa one too?
Give one to Papa too.
What a good girl.